Welcome to the new feature introduction video of Marvelous Designer 2025.
In this video, we will introduce you to the function of IK joint printing.
Since the start of the 2025 version, through the IK joint printing function, you can print the default Google IK joint point of Marvelous Designer on the FBX file imported from the outside.
By printing the IK joint point, you can set up the posture and action files in the software for the virtual model.
Combining the automatic conversion of the new version with the action function, you can easily apply various actions for various virtual models to achieve different matching effects.
First, I use the Mixamo web page to bind Google for virtual models, and then import it into Marvelous Designer.
Please modify the imported file to T-pose posture.
When the file is confirmed,
please import it into Marvelous Designer.
When you import the FBX file,
please note that the object type is selected as virtual model.
The default unit is mm.
Please note that you can select the unit that matches your own file.
Here you can cancel the auto-create arrangement point and the auto-create window.
Because the model we import is T-pose.
Then go to the virtual model option in the main menu,
click on the virtual model editor.
In the virtual model editor,
go to the IK joint option.
Here you can adjust the IK joint setting of the virtual model,
or set up a set of IK joints for the virtual model.
You can choose to manually or automatically set up joints.
For manual setting,
you can click on the name of the IK joint,
then click on the Google joint corresponding to the virtual model,
and set up an IK joint for it.
For example, here,
click on the head,
then you will see the head joint in the test picture.
At this time, there is no corresponding IK joint,
so it is displayed as gray and white.
Now select the head,
click on the virtual model head Google joint,
and complete the setting of the IK joint of the head.
You can repeat the steps until all the joints are set up.
After all the joints that must be set up are set up,
the state will be changed to normal.
In the default state,
the IK joint is symmetrical.
If you need an IK joint that is not symmetrical,
please click here to close the symmetry.
After completing the setting,
select the T-shape position,
then the reset position next to it will be activated.
So far, the IK joint setting has been completed.
Next, let's see how to use automatic setting.
Click on the automatic setting,
you will see the required IK joints have been set up.
As before, select the T-shape position,
then check if the reset position is automatically activated.
After the reset position button is activated,
the IK joint setting is complete.
Then we can go to the asset library,
find the position file of the virtual model,
add a position,
you can see the virtual model that sets the IK joint,
so that the virtual model can be used once,
and you can also call the position or action file
in the shop.
After adding the IK joint,
the virtual model is ready to be used in the asset library.
You can check whether the virtual model is set up
or not.
In the default state,
please click the IK joint setting function.
Now you can choose the position
or action file.
This is how to add and konfirm IK joint.